Why is everybody using these tiny,little lights nowadays?
請問現在為何都用小燈泡？
I remember when people used big ones.
我記得以前都用大燈泡
That's a good story,Grandpa.
錢德爺爺話當年
Wow. Monica's letting other people help decorate her tree?
摩妮卡讓別人佈置她的聖誕樹
Did someone get her drunk again,or...?
誰又把她灌醉了嗎？
Having a perfect tree is not what Christmas is about.
聖誕節的意義不在於聖誕樹
It's about being with loved ones.
而在於與所愛的人共度
That is nice. And we're done. Ta-da!
真好，佈置好了
It just doesn't quite feel like Christmas to me.
我總覺得它少了一股聖誕味
Oh,here.
那這樣呢
See,now it feels like Christmas.
這樣才像聖誕節
The One With The Routine
本集播出：「舞林高手」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
And that's the story of the dreidel.
這就是猶太陀螺的由來
Some people trace the Christmas tree to the Egyptians...
有些人說聖誕樹源自古埃及
who'd bring palm branches into huts on the shortest day of the year...
在每年白畫最短的日子 他們會把棕櫚枝帶進屋裡
symbolizing life's triumph over death.
象徵生命戰勝死亡
And that was,like,4000 years ago.
那是4千年前的事了
Around the same time that you started this story.
你開始講古也差不多是那時候
-Hey,you guys. -Hey. What's up?
你們好 喬伊
I had to get out of the apartment. Janine's stretching all over.
我不出門不行 吉寧到處拉筋
Everywhere I look she's like....
一轉頭就看到她在…
I can see why that's hard to resist.
難怪你無法抗拒
I like her so much.
我好喜歡她
I'm sorry she doesn't feel the same.
可惜她對你沒感覺
I know. And she's so sweet.
就是啊，她好可愛
I just want to feed her grapes and brush her hair.
我好想餵她吃葡萄 幫她梳頭
You are aware that she's not a monkey,right?
你知道她不是猴子吧？
I am so over Janine.
我已經不在乎吉寧了
Yeah,at first I thought she was hot, but now she's like old news.
我原本覺得她很火辣 現在她已經成了過去式
-Hey,guys. -Janine!
你們好 吉寧
I'm gonna be a dancer on a TV special for New Year's Eve.
我剛接到除夕特別節目的通告
It's called some sort of Dickin' Rockin' Dicky Eve.
叫什麼狄克搖滾狄奇之夜的
Hold it.
慢著
Are you talking about Dick Clark's New Year's Rockin' Eve?
是狄剋剋拉克新年搖滾之夜嗎
Yeah,that's what I said.
就是那個
Oh,my God, we love that show!
天哪，我們愛死那個節目了
Ross and I have been watching it since I can remember.
從我有記憶以來 羅斯和我每年都看
You're still just a little fat girl inside, aren't you?
內心深處的你仍是個小胖妹
I'm gonna be one of the party people.
我今年要去當狂歡派對來賓
You're gonna be a party person? Those guys rock the most!
你要當去派對來賓？ 那些人最酷了
They said to bring someone. Want to be my dance partner?
他們叫我帶人去 你願意當我的舞伴嗎？
I would love to spend New Year's with you.
當然，我很願意跟你跨年
They're taping tomorrow. I don't understand why..
明天就要錄影了，我也不太懂
Well,how it works is...
是這樣的
the part with Dick Clark in Times Square is actually live.
時代廣場的部分是現場直播
But they tape some of the party stuff ahead of time.
但他們會預錄狂歡派對的畫面
Not a lot of people know that.
知道的人並不多
Do you guys want to come too?
你們也想去嗎？
-Are you serious? -We are there!
真的還假的？ 一言為定
What are you laughing at?
你笑什麼笑？
Well,I used to date him, but you're still going out with her.
我跟他交往過 但你還跟她在一起
Thanks. Great,so we can all go together.
謝謝…那我們就一起去
I gotta run. I'll catch you later.
我得走了，回頭見
Bye,Janine.
再見 吉寧再見
Did she just ask me out on a date?
她是不是約我了？
I don't think so.
應該不是
She invited him to the biggest party of the millennium.
她找他參加 千禧年最盛大的晚會耶
Yeah,but she also invited you and Ross.
但她也找了你和羅斯
I'm sorry,I don't think that that was a romantic thing.
很抱歉，那應該不算約會
Well, maybe. But,hey, I know how I can find out.
或許吧，但我有一個辦法
It's a New Year's Eve party.
我們不是要參加跨年晚會？
So at midnight,I can kiss her. And if she kisses me back, great.
到了午夜，我可以親她 要是她也回吻，漂亮
If she says, "What are you doing?"
要是她說「你幹什麼？」
I can say, "lt wasn't me, it was New Year's."
我就說「都是新年害的」
That's better than Ross kissing me in high school...
比高中時羅斯想親我要好
and saying that he did it because he needed Chap Stick.
他說他需要護唇膏
It was a dry day.
那天很乾燥
We are going to Dick Clark's New Year's Rockin' Eve!
我們要上狄剋剋拉克跨年晚會
Oh,my God!
我的天哪
我的天啊
Okay,I've been on sets before...
聽著，我錄過影
so let me give you some advice.
我有些建議
It's a show,but we're just dancing. It's no big deal.
雖然是上電視，我們只管跳舞 沒什麼大不了的
Important thing to remember: Stay cool.
最重要的是要酷
-Got it. -Okay.
瞭解
Oh,my God! It's just like I dreamed it!
天哪，跟我夢想的一樣
Everyone! Gather up!
全體集合
-Excuse us! -Excuse us!
借過
The music's gonna start, you're gonna dance...
我們的做法是 音樂一放，你們就跳舞
we'll tape it. Don't look at the camera. Questions?
我們會錄影，你們不要看鏡頭 有問題嗎？
Yeah,I have a question. When is this gonna air?
我有，什麼時候播出？
Yeah. Now,you guys dance over there...
好，你們去那邊跳
you guys,over there. I want you two here.
你們去那邊跳 你們兩個在這裡
Everyone else,spread out.
其他人散開
We'd rather not dance together because we're brother and sister.
我們最好不要配一對 因為我們是兄妹
Yeah,it would seem kind of weird.
對，那樣會有點怪
As weird as coming all the way down here and then having to go home right now?
會比大老遠跑來 卻得立刻滾回家來得怪嗎？
So when is it gonna air?
所以是什麼時候播？
You look in the kitchen, I got the closet.
你找廚房，我找後面的櫃子
I can save you time,ladies. I'm right here.
不必浪費時間了，我在這裡
Yeah. Why don't you take a walk? This doesn't concern you.
錢德，你出去一下 這件事與你無關
We're looking for our presents from Monica.
我們在找摩妮卡送的聖誕禮物
That's terrible.
什麼？太差勁了
No, we do it every year.
不會，我們每年都找
Oh, well, that makes it not terrible.
那就不差勁了
Yeah,we never find them.
但我們沒有找到過
She's always bested us, that wily...minx.
她老是打敗我們，奸詐的查某
We'll search here for an hour...
放心，我們找個1小時
and then we'll go to Joey's and search,okay?
就會換到喬伊那邊找，好嗎？
-You can't look for Monica's presents. -We have to.
不好，你們不能找她送的禮物 我們一定要找
You don't have to. And you can't, because I live here too.
你們不一定要找，也不能找 因為我也住在這裡
Well,then you should look with us.
那你應該跟我們一起找
Why?
為什麼？
Aren't you worried about what to get Monica?
你都不愁要送摩妮卡什麼嗎？
No,I have a great idea for her present.
不會，我有個很棒的構想
Oh,that's it? A great idea? Oh,yeah?
就只有很棒的構想？
What if she gets you a great present...
那樣是不夠的 要是她送你一個大禮
two mediums and lots of little ones...
兩個普通禮和一堆小禮呢？
and you just get her one present? She'll feel bad.
而你只送她一個大禮 她一定會很難過
Why would you do that to her? Why? Why?
你為什麼要讓她難過？ 為什麼…
-If I help,we can find them faster! -Right!
有我幫忙找得更快 沒錯
We have a live one!
逮到一個了
-Oh,it's a Macy's bag! -Yeah.
是梅西百貨的袋子
Who's it for?
這是給誰的？
"Dear losers, do you really think I'd hide presents under the couch?
親愛的俗辣 你們真以為我會藏在沙發下？
P.S. Chandler, I knew they'd break you."
又：錢德，我就知道你會讓步
Uh-oh. She may be onto us.
她可能已經發現了
We are so gonna find them this year.
我們今年一定要找到
You said you'd go across the hall and look. Do you do that every year?
你們剛才說會到對面去找 該不會是每年都去吧？
Yeah.
是啊
You don't go into the back of my closet...
你們沒有到我的櫃子裡面
and look under my gym bag or anything?
翻我的健身袋底下吧？
-No. Never do that. -No.
沒有，從來沒有
That's where Joey gave me stuff to store that I've never seen.
喬伊會托我保管東西 我看都沒看過
Okay, that did not just happen.
剛才的事是幻覺
Here comes a camera.
又有攝影機來了
Right. No biggie. Stay loose.
好，小意思，放輕鬆
Why do they keep doing that?
他們為什麼一直避開？
We have to get up on one of those platforms.
想上鏡頭就得上那些平台
They've been taping them all day.
他們一直拍平台上的人
Right.
沒錯
What'd you guys do to get up on there?
你們為什麼能上去？
We learned how to dance.
我們有練過
When you learned to dance, did you forget how to put on underpants?
你練舞時也忘了穿內褲嗎？
Yeah!
-Hey,you're a good dancer. -Really?
你跳得很好嘛 是嗎？
You'd be better if you loosened your hips.
臀部再放鬆一點會更好
-What do you mean? -Like this.
怎麼說？ 像這樣
That's it. Feel the rhythm. That's better.
就是這樣，跟著節奏擺動 好多了
You're dancing with her.
你去跟那個女生跳
-We're together. -Yeah,we came together.
不，我們是一起來的
I don't see it.
我看不出來
You are dancing with the tall guy. Tall guy,raise your hand!
你去跟那個高個子跳 高個子，舉手
Hey,buddy. Let me dance with her. I like her, and I think I have a shot.
不…老兄，拜託讓我跟她跳 我很喜歡她，我覺得我有機會
Really,you think so? I don't.
你覺得有？我覺得沒有
I couldn't find anything.. Hey,wait!
喬伊那裡什麼都沒… 等等！
Yeah,we found them.
我們找到了
They were in the guest-room closet.
在客房衣櫥的外套後面
You have nothing to worry about because they're crap.
你不必擔心了，都是些爛東西
Those are mine. I got those for you.
那是我要送給你們的禮物
Oh. Thanks,Chandler,they're great!
謝了，好棒喔
Chandler,what is this very weird metal A-Z thing?
這個奇怪的金屬AZ是什麼
Those are bookends. That's a great gift.
那是書擋，是很棒的禮物
Oh. Okay,I'm sorry. Thank you for my "az."
好，抱歉，謝謝你送的AZ （AZ音近屁股ass）
Make sure you put all that stuff back in the closet.
記得放回衣櫃裡，好嗎？
Yes,okay.
好…
By the way,I think it's really nice of you that even after you moved...
對了，你人真好 都搬家了...
you still keep storing that stuff for Joey.
還幫喬伊保管東西
Hey,dancing girl?
喂，舞女
Can I go to the bathroom?
我想上廁所
Here we go. Yeah.
來轉一下 好了
Looking good,Gellers!
很不錯喔，蓋勒兄妹
We know!
還用你說
That snippy guy's the one who decides who gets on the platform.
你看那個拽人 他專門指定上平台的人
-We should go dance by him. -Okay.
我們應該去他面前跳 好
Okay,everybody,hold!
全部暫停
Next on the platforms are....
接下來的平台舞者有…
You two! And....
你們兩個，還有…
-You two! -Cool!
你們兩個
Excuse me,sir?
請問一下
Would it help if I weren't wearing underpants?
如果我不穿內褲會入選嗎？
Monica!
摩妮卡
Would it?
會嗎？
How about me?
那我不穿呢？
Hey,tall guy!
高個子
I want to talk to you about that girl you're dancing with.
我想跟你聊聊你的舞伴
She's nice, huh? To think I almost brought my wife to this.
她真不賴，我還差點帶老婆來
Yeah. Yeah. Okay.
是啊…好
Look,I came with that girl,okay?
老兄，我和她是一起來的
I plan to kiss her at the New Year's countdown.
我想在倒數時吻她
I'm trying to win her over. I..
我想追她 所以能不能…
I don't think so.
不行
You can dance with my partner.
拜託啦，你可以跟我的舞伴跳
She's real mellow.
她跳得強強滾
Look,you dating this girl you came with?
你在跟這個女生交往嗎？
I was hoping after tonight that maybe I could....
我希望過了今晚可以…
No. No. She's fair game if you ask me. Sorry,buddy.
那就是公平競爭，抱歉
All right. Hey.
好吧
Fair is fair. When you're right, you're right. What can I say?
公平競爭 你說得對，我還能說什麼
Are you in second grade?
你是小學生嗎？
Hey, man, you're the one who wet his pants.
尿褲子的是你
Monica would not hide the presents down here.
摩妮卡不會把禮物藏在這裡的
No,but she did. Look,there's that old hippie I've always wanted.
怎麼不會 我一直想要一個老嬉皮
If they are here, Gunther knows about it.
要是藏在這裡，阿甘一定知道
And I could get it out of him. He's had a huge crush on me.
我可以去套他，他很喜歡我
That's not fair to play with his head, though. You do it.
這樣利用他不公平，還是你去
Okay.
好
Hey,Gunther.
阿甘
Hi.
Getting to be that holiday time again,huh?
聖誕佳節又要來了
Yes,it's like a miracle.
聖誕節確實很神奇
I was thinking,since it's the time of giving gifts...
我想說既然到了送禮的季節
I was wondering,are there any presents around here for me?
不知道這裡有沒有我的禮物？
You know what I mean?
你懂我的意思吧
-I think I found them. -That's the Toys for Tots collection bin.
我找到了 那是要捐出去的玩具
-That's awfully convenient,don't you think? -For the tots it is.
很方便不是嗎？ 對捐贈單位來說
-Hey,you guys,guess what. -Did you find them?
你們猜怎樣？ 你找到了嗎？
No,Gunther fainted.
不是，阿甘昏倒了
Man,this sucks.
真討厭
If Mom and Dad don't see us on TV after we made them jealous...
要是跟爸媽愛現完卻沒上電視
then who's gonna be the losers then?
到時候是誰遜？
I know what'll get us up on a platform.
我知道怎樣可以上平台了
What?
怎樣？
The routine!
跳招牌舞
We haven't done the routine since middle school.
我們中學畢業後就沒跳過了
When the snippy guy sees the routine...
等那個拽人看過招牌舞
he'll want to build us our own platform.
搭都會幫我們搭一座平台
Was it that good?
有那麼贊嗎？
We got honorable mention in the brother/sister dance category!
我們得了兄弟姐妹組的特別獎
It's almost fake midnight. Do we really have any other choice?
假午夜快到了，我們還能怎樣
Okay,let's do it.
那好吧
Mom and Dad are gonna be so faced!
爸媽會嫉妒死
Five,six,seven,eight!
五六七八
So do we really need to ask who's going up on the platform next?
接下來該誰上平台還用問嗎？
You get up there and do that again, exactly like that.
不用，你們上去照樣再跳一遍
Get this. Dick will want it for the Bloopers show.
拍下來當漏網鏡頭用
All right,cut! Listen up,everyone!
卡 全體注意
When we start again, it'll be the countdown...
接下來是倒數計時
so I want to see everybody's excitement!
大家要high
Hey,guy!
You got three seconds to get away.
限你3秒鐘之內離開我的舞伴
What's going on here?
怎麼了？
Take a look at the guy's pants!
你看他的褲子
You told us to show excitement, but don't you think he went overboard?
你是叫我們要high 但他也high過頭了吧？
What's the matter with you? Go!
你變態啊？給我出場
Yeah,take a hike,wet pants!
滾啦，失禁男
Can you believe this?
你相信嗎？
We're on the platform for the millennial moment!
進入千禧年時我們會在平台上
I know!
就是啊
You haven't been practicing the routine, have you?
你沒有偷練招牌舞吧？
No.
當然沒有
Me too!
我也有
When the music starts...
回到現場時...
I was thinking about maybe going into the robot.
我想跳機器人舞步
Ross, we should stick to the routine. We don't want to look stupid.
羅斯 跳招牌舞就好，免得丟臉
All right, we're back! Ten seconds left.
回到現場，倒數10秒
-Ten. -Nine,eight.
10，9，8，
-Seven. -Okay,it all comes down to this.
7… 好，這一刻終於來了
Whatever happens,happens.
一切順其自然
Destiny.
聽天由命
three,two,one!
3，2，1
-Cut! -No!
卡 不！
Year!
快樂
Happy "No" Year!
新年不快樂
Now we go to the live shot of Times Square. That's a wrap!
接著是時代廣場的現場畫面 大家辛苦了，收工
What did that snippy guy say?
那個拽人說什麼？
I think he's kicking out anyone who's not dancing.
他把不跳舞的人趕走了
So just keep dancing.
所以繼續跳
Hey,look who I found.
看我找到什麼
Oh,hi,guys!
你們好
Birds have a very good sense of direction.
鳥類的方向感很好
I thought maybe they could help us find the presents.
或許它們可以幫忙找出禮物
Yes,if the presents are hidden south for the winter.
如果禮物藏在南方過冬的話
Or we could just follow your clever jokes. Any ideas? Didn't think so.
順著你的笑話去找也行 你知道在哪裡嗎？當然不知道
Come on,show us where the presents are.
來，把禮物找出來
The duck seems to think that Monica got me garbage.
鴨子似乎認為摩妮卡送我垃圾
I wonder what I could get Monica that's as good as garbage.
什麼樣的回禮能跟垃圾一樣好
How about my "az"?
我的AZ如何？
-Hey. This is hollow. -What?
這是空的 什麼？
This bench,it's hollow. I can't believe I never knew that!
這排座椅是空心的 我居然都不知道
-Oh,the presents! -Don't look directly at them!
我們的禮物 不！不要直視它們
What?
什麼？
All right,no,we could look at them.
沒事，可以看
This one's for me!
這是我的
This one's for Chandler. Here.
這是錢德的，拿去
-And the big one's for me! -Oh,let's open them!
大包的是我的 趕快拆來看
-Wait a minute. We can't do this. -Why?
等等，我們不能這樣 為什麼？
I don't want to know what Monica got me.
我不想知道摩妮卡送我什麼
I'm sure she worked hard at getting it and wanting to surprise me.
她一定很用心的替我找禮物 想給我驚喜
And you guys are gonna ruin that.
你們這樣會壞事
We have to put these back. This is not what Christmas is about.
我們得把禮物放回去 這樣不叫聖誕節
Whatever,Linus. I'm opening mine.
誰理你，我要拆我的
Nobody is opening anything, okay?
誰也不准拆
I want to see the look on her face when I give her my present.
我不知道你們怎麼想 但我想看摩妮卡收到我禮物的表情
I'm sure she wants to see the look on my face when I get mine.
她一定也想看 我收到禮物的表情
So,please,please,can we just...? Can we put them back?
所以求求你們放回去
-Will you get us better gifts? -Fine.
你會送我們更好的禮物嗎？ 好啦
Hey,guys.
我回來了
You found the presents?
你們找到禮物了？
You let them find the presents?
錢德，你讓她們找到？
Great.
帥啊
Do you know how long it took me to find you that water purifier?
你知道那個濾水器多難找嗎？
-That's what you got me? -Yes,I see. That look is priceless.
你送我濾水器？ 這下我懂了，你的表情真棒
Home sweet home,huh?
甜蜜的家
Nice to get back to reality.
回到現實真好
Plus,we know how the New Year's gonna go off.
我們也知道新年會怎樣了
I guess there's no reason for all that Y2K panic,you know?
千禧蟲根本沒什麼，對吧？
Anyway,good night.
好吧，晚安
-Joey? -Yeah?
喬伊 怎樣？
Three...
3...
two,one.
2，1
Happy New Year.
新年快樂
What was that for?
這是幹什麼？
Tonight when they yelled "cut" and we didn't get to kiss...
今晚當他們喊卡 我們沒能接吻
I was really,really disappointed, and I just....
我真的很失望 我真的…
I just really wanted to kiss you.
真的很想親你
Really?
真的？
In the moment,I really wanted to kiss you too. In the moment.
那時候我也很想親你… 那時候
-In the moment. -But only in the moment.
那時候 只有那時候
So do you want to kiss again?
你…想再親一次嗎？
Sure. New Year's Eve is only two weeks away.
想啊，離除夕只有2個星期
Can you wait?
你能等嗎？
No.
不能
Me neither.
我也是
Three,two....
3，2…
You don't have to count down every time we kiss.
不必每次接吻都倒數
Oh. Okay.
好
Except I sort of felt like I needed a couple seconds to get ready.
但我覺得我需要幾秒鐘做準備
We were on the platform,ready to dance into the new millennium...
我們在平台上 準備帶全世界跳進千禧年
and the guy yells,"Cut!"
那傢伙卻喊了卡
-So Joey didn't get to kiss Janine? -Nope,he sure didn't.
所以喬伊也沒親到吉寧？ 當然沒有
I guess that means that you guys are still tied.
所以你和喬伊還是平分秋色羅
I don't know about that. I think she saw us do our routine.
那可不見得 她應該看到我們的招牌舞了
I may have boogied right into first place.
我用布吉舞步打頭陣
So you guys are telling me that you actually did...
等等，你們真的跳了
the routine from eighth grade?
八年級的招牌舞？
Yeah! But of course we had to update it a little bit.
對，不過當然得稍做修正
Hey, by the way, quick thinking about catching me.
你反應真快，知道要接住我
There's no way you could've done the end...
我正想說 你們絕不可能...
the way you guys did it back then.
照以前的結尾跳
What? We could do it.
什麼？當然可以
I don't know. You were a lot bigger.. I mean,stronger back then.
不行吧，你以前胖…壯多了
I can do it,okay?
我可以，好嗎？
Come on,let's go! Come on.
來吧
One,two,three,four...
一二三四
five,six,seven,eight.
五六七八
I can't do it!
我不行
Now,you do that,you're on TV.
那樣跳就能上電視了